A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Office Files of William D. Carmichael FA711
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Office Files of William D. Carmichael
1964-1990
Rockefeller Archive Center
Carmichael, William D. (William Daniel) (1929)
Ford Foundation
FA711
17.75 Cubic Feet 48 boxes (45 letter document boxes, 2 half letter document containers, 1 legal document container)
Scope and Contents
The Office Files of William D. Carmichael document Ford Foundation overseas grants during the period 1968-1989, with an emphasis on the 1980s. The bulk of the records concern Carmichael's work as Vice President, Developing Country Programs, and consist of correspondence, memos and reports pertaining to the administration and grant activities of Ford Foundation field offices around the world. The collection also documents the relationship between overseas offices of the Ford Foundation and the headquarters in New York City. There are substantial records documenting Carmichael's travel and attendance at conferences, his participation in Board of Trustee meetings and his role in coordinating Board meetings convened overseas. Also included are budget planning records, program review documents, and subject files relating to numerous program initiatives and administrative matters of concern to Carmichael. The collection is particularly rich in material concerning the daily operations of field offices around the world, Ford Foundation-funded educational programs in South Africa, and the international component of the Foundation's Women's Program.
Arrangement
The Office Files of William D. Carmichael are arranged in eight series:
1. Field Offices, 1972-1989
2. South Africa, 1974-1988
3. Conferences, Meetings and Trips, 1981-1988
4. Program Budget, 1982-1989
5. Subjects, 1968-1989
6. Board of Trustees, 1978-1989
7. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971-1989
8. Reports and Program Files, 1964-1990
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. The entirety of Series 6: Board of Trustees, 1978-1989 is restricted from access. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
William D. Carmichael's material arrived at the RAC in three accessions between 2011 and 2019. The material that arrived in 2011 and 2012 was processed as two separate collections at the RAC. When another box of Carmichael material arrived at the RAC in 2019, all of Carmichael's files were consolidated into one collection and brought up to standard processing by Katie Martin in February 2020.
The material in Series 1-6 came to the RAC in 2012 as Accession 2012:068 [Boxes 30272-30275, 30277-30280, 30282, 47940-47942]. The material was received by the Ford Foundation archive staff in 1990. This material was originally arranged and described by Jim Moske, Ford Foundation Archives, in 2006.
The material that comprises Series 7: Chronological Correspondence Files came to the RAC in 2011 as Accession 2011:075. The material was originally processed by Brian Bleich and Nancy Ng Tam, The Winthrop Group, in August 2011 as a standalone collection, A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Correspondence Files of William D. Carmichael (FA522). This material became Series 7 of Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Office Files of William D. Carmichael in February 2020.
Series 8 is comprised of material from Accession 2019:101 [Box 40044] that was originally separated from the rest of Carmichael's papers. The box arrived at the RAC from the Ford Foundation in 2019. The materials were processed and added to this collection by Katie Martin in February 2020.
Biographical / Historical
William D. Carmichael was Vice President of the Ford Foundation, Developing Country Programs from 1981-1989. The administration of the Ford Foundation international programs was dramatically restructured in 1980-1981, and a new office for Developing Country Programs was created. William D. Carmichael was appointed Vice President of this new area in March 1981. Carmichael oversaw the work of Foundation field offices, and of New York-based staff responsible for grants to developing countries.
Prior to his role as Vice President, he was Head of the Middle East and Africa Office (1977-1981), Head of the Office for Latin America and the Caribbean (1971-1977) and Representative in the Brazil Office (1968-1971). Dr. Carmichael retired from the Ford Foundation on September 30, 1989. Key accomplishments of Carmichael's tenure as Vice President include his role in advancing the development of a Women's Program, financing for worldwide activities in community resource management, the expansion of Foundation activities throughout southern Africa. Carmichael and his staff played a leading role within the U.S. philanthropic and scholarly communities in the formulation of policies towards the apartheid regime in South Africa. After leaving the Ford Foundation, he became executive director for Soviet Union and Eastern European Programs at the Institute of International Education until 1993.
Born on September 5, 1929, Dr. William D. Carmichael received a B.A. in Economics from Yale in 1950. In 1952 he received an M.P.A. in Public and International Affairs and an M.A. in Economics from Princeton University. He received a BLitt from Oxford University in Economics in 1955, and was awarded a PhD in Economics by Princeton in 1959. Before working at the Foundation, Dr. Carmichaeel was Dean of Cornell University's Graduate School of Business and Public Administration from 1962 until 1968.
- Field Offices, 1972-1989; 1; 3.8 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, press clippings and other records that document program development, grantmaking and grantee activities. Also included are records concerning the establishment, administration and daily operations of overseas offices. Numerous memos and reports written by Program Officers include vivid accounts of the political scene, current events and social and economic conditions in their host countries. Many reports contain general histories of regions or countries, as well as overviews of Foundation activities in these areas. Also included are files concerning the opening of new offices in China and Zimbabwe, and on transferring the West Africa office from Lagos, Nigeria to Dakar, Senegal. The bulk of the series dates from the 1980s, though scattered memos and reports from the 1970s are also present.
  Arrangement
  The records are arranged alphabetically by the region, with further sub-division by program officer.
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Buenos Aires, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Consolidation, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - General, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Hall, Gridley, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Lima office consultation – Lowenthal, Abraham, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Puryear, Jeffrey M. (Representative), 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Recife, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Andes and Southern Cone - Saint, William S., 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bangladesh - Bailey, Charles (Representative), 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bangladesh - Bottrall, Anthony, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bangladesh - General, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bangladesh - Germain, Adrienne, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brazil - Dassin, Joan (Representative), 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brazil - Fry, Peter, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Brazil - General, 1981-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brazil - Reichmann, Rebecca, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Brazil - Sanderson, Steven, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Brazil - Sellers, Patricia, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brazil - Welna, Christopher, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - China - Geithner, Peter F. (Representative), 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - China - General, 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Booker, Salih, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - General, 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 26-29)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Harare, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 30-31, Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Howard, Craig, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Hyden, Goran, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 34-37)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Jones, David, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Nairobi office, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Saint, William (Representative), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa - Saulniers, Suzanne, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Chen, Lincoln C. (Representative), 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 43-45)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Conway, Gordon R. (Representative), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Elliott, Carolyn M., 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - General, 1976-1989 (Box 6, Folder 48-49)
  - India, Nepal and Sri Lanka - Sudarshan, R., 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Latin American and Caribbean, 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Mexico and Central America - Cleaves, Peter S., 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Mexico and Central America - Cox, Stephen (Representative), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Mexico and Central America - General, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Mexico and Central America - Welna, Christopher, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Mexico and Central America - Winder, David, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Barsalou, Judy, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Cairo Office – Bundy visit, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Middle East and North Africa - General, 1975-1989 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Gerhart, John D., 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 60-61)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Lesch, Ann M., 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Nygaard, David (Representative), 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Playfair, Emma, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Sudan, 1981-1988 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Middle East and North Africa - Travers, Lee (Representative), 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Southeast Asia - General, 1980-1986 (Box 8, Folder 67-68)
  - Southeast Asia - Kessinger, Tom (Representative), 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Southeast Asia - Korten, Frances, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Southeast Asia - Office closures, 1973, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Southeast Asia - Philippines, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Southeast Asia - Vietnam, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Southeast Asia - Winder, David (Representative), 1983-1989 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - West Africa - Dakar, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 75-76)
  - West Africa - Duggan, William (Representative), 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - West Africa - Ellsworth, Lynn, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - West Africa - General, 1978-1989 (Box 9, Folder 79, Box 10, Folder 80)
  - West Africa - Horovitz, Richard A. (Representative), 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - West Africa - Ivory Coast – Edwards visit, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - West Africa - Joseph, Richard, 1985-1988 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - West Africa - Kubisch, Ann, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - West Africa - Lagos, 1981-1989 (Box 10, Folder 85-86)
  - West Africa - Tragar, Lillian, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 87)
- South Africa, 1974-1988; 2; 0.76 Cubic Feet
  Correspondence, memoranda and supporting documents concerning grantmaking and investment in South Africa by the Ford Foundation and other organizations. Includes files of Assistant Program Officer David Bonbright, and records of a committee of foundation and university executives convened by the Carnegie Corporation to promote better educational opportunities for black South Africans.
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Bonbright, David, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Consortium on Educational Opportunities for Black South Africans, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 89-91)
  - Firestone, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Fund for Education in South Africa, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - General, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 94-95, Box 12, Folder 96-101)
- Conferences, Meetings and Trips, 1981-1988; 3; 1.9 Cubic Feet
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, agendas, reports, program submissions and briefing materials relating to William Carmichael's travel abroad on Foundation business, and his attendance at conferences and meetings worldwide. Events documented in these files include Ford Foundation staff meetings, field office site visits and conferences sponsored by other organizations. Of particular importance are extensive files on the 1985 United Nations Nairobi Conference marking the end of the Women's Decade, the 1983 meetings of the Ford Foundation International Affairs and Human Rights and Social Justice programs in Geneva, Switzerland, and a 1982 New York meeting of Indian Prime Minister Indira Gandhi with representatives of American philanthropies.
  Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Miscellaneous – United States, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 102)
  - Immigration and Refugee Conference, Williamsburg, VA, 1981 November (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - Lima, Peru and Bogota, Colombia, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 104)
  - Miscellaneous – Overseas, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 105)
  - Miscellaneous – United States, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 106)
  - Prime Minister Indira Gandhi New York visit, 1982 August (Box 13, Folder 107)
  - Miscellaneous – Overseas, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - Miscellaneous – United States, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - African-American Institute Conference, Harare, Zimbabwe, 1983 January (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - International Affairs/Human Rights meeting, Geneva, Switzerland, 1983 January (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Indonesia Trip File, 1983 March-April (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - International University Foundation Conference, Ditchley Park, 1983 August (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - Buenos Aires, Argentina Trip, 1984 January (Box 14, Folder 114)
  - Central America Trip, Briefing Book, 1984 January (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Mexico Trip, Briefing Book, 1984 January (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Mexico/Central America Trip, Miscellaneous records, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Santiago-Lima Trip, 1984 January (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Employment and Income Generation meeting, Bangladesh, 1984 April (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - International Affairs meeting, Mexico, 1984 April - May (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Settling International Disputes Conference, Ditchley Park, Trip File, 1984 May 11-13 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Egypt and Israel, 1984 June (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - Latin American and Caribbean Dinner, Washington, D.C., 1984 July (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - Southern Africa Trip, 1984 July (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - Prospects for Peace in the Middle East Conference, Council on Foreign Relations, New York, 1984 September (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Dakar, Senegal Trip, 1985 January (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - Haiti Trip, 1985 January (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - SACHED Trust donors' meeting, Geneva, Switzerland, 1985 February (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - Nicaragua Trip, 1985 March (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - Human Rights meeting, Ica, Peru, 1985 March (Box 15, Folder 130)
  - Israel and South Africa Trip, 1985 April (Box 15, Folder 131)
  - Southeast Asia Trip, Education and Culture meeting, Bali, 1985 May (Box 15, Folder 132)
  - Thailand Trip, Briefing Book, 1985 May (Box 15, Folder 133)
  - Washington, D.C. - Meeting with University Presidents Regarding South Africa, 1985 June (Box 15, Folder 134)
  - International Affairs meeting, Paraty, Brazil, 1985 June - July (Box 15, Folder 135)
  - End of Women's Decade Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, 1985 July (Box 15, Folder 136-137, Box 16, Folder 138)
  - Washington, D.C. Trip, World Bank/Africa programs, 1985 September (Box 16, Folder 139)
  - South Africa Trip, 1985 November (Box 16, Folder 140)
  - Buenos Aires, Argentina Trip, 1985 December (Box 16, Folder 141)
  - Mexico Trip, 1986 January (Box 16, Folder 142)
  - South Africa Trip, 1986 February (Box 16, Folder 143)
  - Child Survival/Population meeting, Katmandu, Nepal, 1986 April (Box 16, Folder 144)
  - Boston Trip (Re: OXFAM), 1986 June (Box 16, Folder 145)
  - China Trip, 1986 June - July (Box 16, Folder 146)
  - South Africa Trip, 1986 July - August (Box 16, Folder 147)
  - Lagos, Nigeria Trip, 1986 August (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Nairobi, Kenya Trip, 1986 August (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - European Trip, 1986 September (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - "Enabling Environment" Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, 1986 October (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - European Trip, 1986 November (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Rural Poverty and Resources meeting, Nairobi, Kenya, 1986 November (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - South Africa Trip, 1986 November - December (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - African-American Institute Conference, Gaborone, Botswana, 1987 January (Box 16, Folder 155-156)
  - Education Policies for Sub-Saharan Africa, Paris, France, 1987 January (Box 16, Folder 157)
  - Human Rights and Governance meeting, London, England, 1987 January (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - Haiti Trip, 1987 February (Box 16, Folder 159)
  - Angola Trip, 1987 March (Box 16, Folder 160)
  - Lima, Peru Trip, 1987 May (Box 17, Folder 161)
  - Angolan Economy/African-American Institute Conferences, Tarrytown, 1987 June (Box 17, Folder 162)
  - Nicaragua Trip, 1987 June (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - South Africa Trip, 1987 September (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - 18th African-American Institute Conference, Aspen Institute, Maryland, 1987 November (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - West Africa Trip, 1987 November (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - World Health Organization (WHO) AIDS Conference, Geneva, Switzerland, 1987 November (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Ditchley Foundation Conference: Future of the Front-Line States in Southern Africa, 1988 January (Box 17, Folder 168)
  - Latin America staff meeting, 1988 February (Box 17, Folder 169)
  - Non-Profit and International Organizations Forum, Columbia University, 1988 February (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Haiti Trip, 1988 March (Box 17, Folder 171)
  - Indonesia Trip, 1988 March (Box 17, Folder 172)
  - Asia-Plus, Rural Poverty and Governance staff meeting, Bangalore, India, 1988 April (Box 17, Folder 173)
  - Colloquium on Development, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1988 May (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - 1.) Staff Meetings on Livelihoods, Employment, and Income Generation, 2.) Symposium on Expanding Income Opportunities for Women in Poverty, Nairobi, Kenya, 1988 May (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - South Africa Trip, 1988 May (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - American Grantmaking in South Africa at the Kaiser Family Foundation, Washington, D.C., 1988 June (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Haiti Trip, 1988 June (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Philippines Trip, 1988 August (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Education Initiatives for Black South Africans, Oxford, England, 1988 September (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - North-South Roundtable Meeting on Southern Africa, Juliasdal, Zimbabwe, 1988 December (Box 17, Folder 181)
- Program Budget, 1982-1989; 4; 1.14 Cubic Feet
  Program budget submissions and related documentation from DCP and a few other Foundation divisions. Many files include substantive reports on the political, social, and economic climates of various countries in which the Foundation had offices. The Program Review files contained in Series V are closely related to these budget materials.
  - Andes and Southern Cone, 1982-1989 (Box 18, Folder 182-183)
  - Bangladesh, 1982-1989 (Box 18, Folder 184-185)
  - Brazil, 1982-1987 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Child Survival/Fair Start, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Caribbean and Latin America, 1982-1987 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - China, 1984-1989 (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - Developing Country Programs, 1984-1988 (Box 18, Folder 190-191)
  - Eastern and Southern Africa, 1982-1989 (Box 19, Folder 192-193)
  - Education and Culture, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - Foundation-wide, 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 195)
  - Governance and Public Policy, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 196)
  - Human Rights and Social Justice, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - India, Nepal, Sri Lanka, 1982-1989 (Box 19, Folder 198-199)
  - International Affairs, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - Israel, 1982-1987 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - Mexico and Central America, 1982-1989 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - Middle East and North Africa, 1982-1989 (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - Rural Poverty and Resources, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 204)
  - South Africa, 1982-1987 (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Southeast Asia, 1982-1989 (Box 20, Folder 206)
  - Urban Poverty, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 207)
  - West Africa, 1982-1989 (Box 20, Folder 208)
- Subjects, 1968-1989; 5; 4.65 Cubic Feet
  Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Series contains records concerning miscellaneous program initiatives, administrative matters, outside organizations and topics of general interest to Carmichael. Included are DCP program review files, memos and reports concerning the origins of the Women's Program and the Health, Nutrition and Population Program, and correspondence concerning the Bilateral Commission on United States-Mexican Relations (access to the latter is restricted from access).
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research, with select files are restricted from access as noted.
  - Affirmative Action - External, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - Affirmative Action – Ford Foundation Policy, 1974-1978 (Box 20, Folder 210)
  - AIDS Task Force, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 211)
  - Atlanta University, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 212)
  - Bilateral Commission on the Future of U.S.-Mexican Relations, 1984-1989 (Box 21, Folder 213)
    Restricted - Executive Search - Open in 2029
  - Bilateral Commission on the Future of U.S.-Mexican Relations, 1984-1989 (Box 21, Folder 214-218)
  - Boston University Health Policy Institute, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 219)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Current Issue Review Group on Cuba, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 220)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Discussion Group on African Development, 1972-1976 (Box 22, Folder 221)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Discussion Group on the Soviet Union in Africa, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 222)
  - Education - Myers, Robert G., 1981-1984 (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - Ethnic Conflict in Developing Countries, 1977-1982 (Box 22, Folder 224-225)
  - External Advisory Panel on Education, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 226)
  - Financial accounting software, 1986-1989 (Box 22, Folder 227)
  - Fulbright Exchange Program Conference, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 228)
  - Health, Nutrition and Population, 1976-1981 (Box 23, Folder 229-233)
  - Human Rights, 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 234)
  - Institute of Cultural Affairs, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 235)
  - International Division Conference, 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 236)
  - International Division Conference – Special Papers, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 237)
  - International Division Education Conference, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 238)
  - International Economic Order, 1975-1979 (Box 24, Folder 239)
  - International Human Rights Internship Program, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 240)
  - International Security and Arms Control, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 241)
  - Interns, 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 242)
  - Korten, David C., 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folder 243)
  - Liberian refugees, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 244)